A Guide to the Social Science Research Council records, Administration and Officers Files, Committee on Problems and Policy (P&P) FA1417
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council records, Administration and Officers Files, Committee on Problems and Policy (P&P)
1985-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council
FA1417
5.32 Cubic Feet 14 letter document boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged in one series: Meeting Files, 1985-1996
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records in this collection were received by the Rockefeller Archive Center from the Social Science Research Council in 2016 and 2017.
Scope and Contents
The collection is primarily comprised of meeting minutes and agendas of the Social Science Research Council's Committee on Problems and Policy. The collection also contains few files pertaining to meetings of the Board of Directors, special meetings, Executive Committee meetings, and prospective committee members.
Biographical / Historical
The Social Science Research Council's Committee on Problems and Policy was formed in 1925 as the Council's central planning body. The committee's members were elected scholars who reviewed the programs of the working committees that carried out the Council's programs.
Meetings
- Meeting Files, 1985-1996; 1; 5.32 Cubic Feet 14 letter document boxes
  Scope and Contents
  The series is primarily comprised of meeting minutes and agendas of the SSRC's Committee on Problems and Policy, the Council's central planning body.
  - Committee on Problems and Policy (P&P) Meeting Minutes, 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1-4, Box 2, Folder 5-8, Box 3, Folder 9-12, Box 4, Folder 13-16, Box 5, Folder 17-20, Box 6, Folder 21-23, Box 7, Folder 24-26, Box 8, Folder 27-29, Box 9, Folder 30-31)
  - Committee on Problems and Policy (P&P) Meeting Agendas, 1988-1994 (Box 9, Folder 32-33, Box 10, Folder 34-37)
  - Meetings of the Board and Committee on Problems and Policy (P&P) - Agendas and Minutes, 1986-1994 (Box 11, Folder 38-41, Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Potential New Committee Members - Appendices, 1993-1995 (Box 12, Folder 43-45, Box 13, Folder 46-48)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Schedule and Agenda, 1986 December 11-13 (Box 14, Folder 49-50)
  - Special Meeting of the Committee on Problems and Policy (P&P) - Minutes, 1995 September 15 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Meeting of the Board of Directors Minutes, 1986 June 10 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Special Meeting of the Board Agenda, 1986 December 12 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Appendix 10 - Review of the International Programs at the SSRC, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Membership Directory: SSRC Committee and Working Groups, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Folder 55)